History moves on.
Train Dreams is a drama film directed by Clint Bentley.
A logger leads a life of quiet grace as he experiences love and loss during
an era of monumental change in early 20th-century America.
Robert Grainier, played by Joel Edgerton.
Gladys Grainier, played by Felicity Jones.
Arn Peeples, played by William H. Macy.
Claire Thompson, played by Kerry Condon.
Ignatius Jack, played by Nathaniel Arcand.
Boomer, played by Clifton Collins Jr..
Train Dreams is a 2025 American period drama film directed by Clint Bentley, who co-wrote
the screenplay with Greg Kwedar, based on the 2011 novella by Denis Johnson.
The film stars Joel Edgerton, Felicity Jones, Nathaniel Arcand, Clifton Collins
Jr., John Diehl, Paul Schneider, Kerry Condon, and William H.
Macy, with narration from Will Patton.
Train Dreams had its world premiere at the 2025 Sundance Film Festival on January 26, 2025, and was released in select
cinemas in the United States on November 7, 2025, before its streaming debut by Netflix on November 21, 2025.
The film received critical acclaim, with praise going to
Bentley's direction and Edgerton's performance.
Among its accolades, the film was named as one of the top ten films of 2025 by
both the National Board of Review and the American Film Institute.
For his performance, Edgerton was nominated for a Golden Globe Award.
It received four nominations at the 98th Academy Awards,
including Best Picture and Best Adapted Screenplay.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, based on
novel or book, slice of life, lumberjack, logger.
The tone is emotional.